Inventory of the Willbur Fisk Papers: Correspondence to Willbur Fisk, 1812 - 1839
Willbur Fisk Papers: Correspondence to Willbur Fisk, 1812 - 1839
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Fisk, Willbur.
1000-91
3.0
6
Willbur Fisk (1792-1839) was a Methodist minister and the first president of Wesleyan University.
Correspondence to Willbur Fisk contains letters sent by others to Fisk, arranged in alphabetical order by sender's name. For the complete finding aid to the Willbur Fisk Papers, visit http://www.wesleyan.edu/libr/schome/FAs/fi1000-91.html.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Materials collected by the college library in the 19th century.
Biographical Note
Willbur Fisk, Wesleyan’s first president, was born on 31 August 1792 and grew up in Brattleboro, Vermont. Although his mother feared that godlessness and sin in schools and colleges would make Fisk too worldly and strangle the spiritual life, Fisk graduated from Brown University in 1815, after also attending Peacham Academy and the University of Vermont. Surprisingly, given his future role at Wesleyan, Fisk was not initially drawn to the Methodist ministry following school. In fact, he struggled with his spiritual purpose at that time, working in law and as a tutor. However, a revelation during a bout of illness brought him to the ministry in 1818, and he devoted the rest of his life to his work as a Methodist. In 1825, Fisk was appointed principal of Wesleyan Academy in Wilbraham, Massachusetts, a preparatory school from which many Wesleyan University students were to be drawn.
When the decision to found a university in Middletown, Connecticut was made, Fisk was tapped for the role of first president. In his inaugural speech in 1831, he outlined his vision for the university, encapsulated by the statement that Education should be directed in reference to two objects—the good of the individual educated and the good of the world. Fisk was deeply involved in the administrative and curricular decisions of Wesleyan, and raised funds for the new college. He traveled to Europe to study educational institutions and collect scientific equipment in 1835-1836, and also took that time as a break from the stresses of the presidency. Suffering from ill-health his entire life, Fisk finally succumbed on 22 February 1839 while still serving as president.
Collection Overview
Correspondence to Willbur Fisk contains letters sent by others to Fisk, arranged in alphabetical order by sender's name. For the complete finding aid to the Willbur Fisk Papers, visit http://www.wesleyan.edu/libr/schome/FAs/fi1000-91.html.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Correspondence to Willbur Fisk
  For the complete finding aid to the Willbur Fisk Papers, visit http://www.wesleyan.edu/libr/schome/FAs/fi1000-91.html.
  The number in parentheses indicates the number of letters from that particular correspondent in the collection.
  - Abbot, Fidelia B. and Clarissa F., 8 May 1838-10 November 1838 (3) (Box 1)
  - Abbott, Gorham, 11 February 1837 (1)
  - Abbott, Jacob, 7 May 1835-14 July 1835 (2)
  - Abernathy, James, 7 August 1834 (1)
  - Adams, Charles, 27 March 1828-11 November 1838 and undated (9)
  - Adams, Henry, 4 December 1837 (1)
  - Adams, J. F., 3 October 1827-14 October 1830 (2)
  - Adams, Parmelee & Company, 4 October 1832-28 March 1835 and undated (5)
  - Agarer, Horace, 4 April 1838 (1)
  - Akers, Peter, 19 April 1834-27 August 1834 (2)
  - Alden, R. 13 September 1836-8 September 1838 (2)
  - Alder, Amelia, 6 June 1837 (1)
  - Allen, Stephen, 28 December 1837 (1)
  - Allen, William H., 9 September 1834-29 September 1834 (2)
  - Alley, J. 27 November 1838 (1)
  - Allton, Mary Fisk, 11 July 1812-7 June 1838 (9)
  - Allton, Oren, 3 February 1830-7 October 1837 (5)
  - Allyn, Job, 1834-22 December 1837 (4)
  - Allyn, Robert, 8 January 1838-16 April 1838 (2)
  - Alverson, James, 6 October 1838 (1)
  - Anders, James O., 10 December 1834 (1)
  - Anderson, Henry James, 4 May 1835 (1)
  - Anderson, William, 17 November 1831-20 September 1837 (12)
  - Anson, William, 15 April 1835 (1)
  - Anthon, Charles, 19 June 1839 (1)
  - Anthony, H., 14 August 1828- 9 September 1833 (2)
  - Anthony, Jane, 16 December 1834 (1)
  - Archer, Philmer W., 3 September 1838 (1)
  - Archibald, N., 24 November 1828-6 December 1828 (2)
  - Armstrong & Plaskis, Company, 21 December 1832-6 April 1835 (7)
  - Armstrong, Conway, 10 March 1832 (1)
  - Austin, G. F., 22 July 1833 (1)
  - Avery, Abraham, 1 March 1826 (1)
  - Avery, B. F., 3 August 1833 (1)
  - Avery, E. K., 21 January 1834 (1)
  - Ayres, Daniel, 30 July 1838-20 September 1838 (2)
  - Ayres, Ezra and others, 10 August 1830 (1)
  - Ayres, Joseph, 10 July 1837 (1)
  - Babbitt, Betsey E., 18 October 1831 (1)
  - Bacheler, Origen, 2 February 1835-7 November 1838 (2)
  - Backus, W. H., 13 June 1833-16 August 1833 (3)
  - Bagnall, Thomas, 10 August 1836 (1)
  - Bailey, John, 5 February 1834 (1)
  - Baird, D. R., 28 February 1838 (1)
  - Baker, Charles, 31 March 1838 (1)
  - Baker, Osmon Cleander, 15 August 1832-25 April 1838 (5)
  - Baldwin, Henry Jr., 7 May 1830 (1)
  - Ball, B. Finette, 7 September 1833 (1)
  - Ball, John, 14 May 1830 (1)
  - Bangs, Elijah K., 20 July 1835 (1)
  - Bangs, Heman, 30 December 1830-15 February 1839 (12)
  - Bangs, Nathan, 13 September 1828-7 February 1839 (20)
  - Bangs, William M., 18 September 1831-18 December 1832 (4)
  - Bannister, Henry, August 1837-24 March 1838 (2)
  - Barber, Cicero, 27 February 1832 (1)
  - Barber, J. 13 March 1838 (1)
  - Barber, Noyes 19 January 1832 (1)
  - Barker, Isaac, 18 May 1831 (1)
  - Barker, John, 3 August 1834 (1)
  - Barnard, Henry, 15 June 1838-18 July 1838 (2)
  - Barnes, John, 30 July 1833-28 April 1835 (2)
  - Barratt, Joseph, 13 May 1836 (1)
  - Barris, Joseph S., 25 April 1833 (1)
  - Barry, Basil, 20 February 1832 (1)
  - Bascom, H. B. 12 December 1834-17 August 1838 (4)
  - Baskerville, John Taft, undated (1)
  - Bates, Dexter, 23 January 1839 (1)
  - Bates, Elizur, 10 May 1833-18 September 1838 (3)
  - Bates, John, 21 February 1831 (1)
  - Beach, Shelton, 2 May 1835 (1)
  - Beecham, John, 31 March 1837-22 October 1836 (2)
  - Bell, S. F., June 1838-7 February 1839 (2)
  - Bement, Jesper, 7 August 1837 (1)
  - Bennett, A. A., 9 April 1830 (1)
  - Bernard, Lr. Gen., 28 November 1835 (1)
  - Bidwell, Ira M., 23 September 1834-19 November 1834 (3)
  - Binings, James, 28 May 1835 (1)
  - Binney, Amos, 2 February 1829-19 June 1837 (3)
  - Birney, James G., 20 September 1830-23 September 1830 (2)
  - Bishop, Charles, 23 February 1833 (1)
  - Bishop, H. 8 December 1836 (1)
  - Bishop, William, 6 September 1837 (1)
  - Bissell, John, 12 September 1828 (1)
  - Black, M. G., 3 April 1834 (1)
  - Black, William, 30 October 1827-4 March 1828 (2)
  - Blackstock, Eleanor, 27 March 1837 (1)
  - Blackstock, James, 19 August 1835 (1)
  - Blake, A. V., 26 December 1838 (1)
  - Blake, John L., 13 February 1834-8 March 1835 (2)
  - Blatchly, Ellsworth, 30 June 1838 (1)
  - Bliss, Abel, 20 January 1831-27 June 1834 (2)
  - Bliss, Fanny, 18 May 1835 (1)
  - Bliss, J. J., 6 December 1832 (1)
  - Bliss, Nancy, 4 September 1829 (1)
  - Blydenburgh, Moses, 27 July 1838 (1)
  - Bolster, Cyrus, 21 June 1838 (1)
  - Bonney, J., 21 July 1837 (1)
  - Booth, W., 18 April 1838-13 July 1838 (3)
  - Borden, S., 17 March 1832-11 March 1834 (2)
  - Boring, Jesse, 18 May 1833 (1)
  - Boucher, Ph., undated (1)
  - Bowie, John, 4 April 1832 (1)
  - Boyd, J. H., 18 December 1832 (1)
  - Bradley, Hanover, 9 October 1834 (1)
  - Bragdon, C. P., 1838 (1)
  - Brainerd, Robert and others, 20 May 1828 (1)
  - Brayton, Daniel, 6 November 1824-2 June 1837 (7)
  - Brent, Daniel, 3 July 1832 (1)
  - Brewer, C., 18 February 1833 (1)
  - Brewer, Susan, 29 September 1829-12 January 1834 (25)
  - Brewster, Walter, December 1831 (1)
  - Brigham, J. C., 10 March 1831-12 April 1837 (4)
  - Brodhead, John, 10 August 1833 (1)
  - Brooks, George, 1825 (1)
  - Brooks, Isham, 28 March 1831 (1)
  - Brown, Charles Lee, 25 February 1834 (1)
  - Brown, David F., 8 July 1837 (1)
  - Brown, Edwin C., 18 August 1831 (1)
  - Brown Joseph, 4 February 1833 (1)
  - Brown, John W., 18 May 1837 (1)
  - Brown, Thomas, 22 December 1830-22 January 1834 (25)
    Father of Charles L. Brown.
  - Brown, William C., 5 August 1835-2 May 1838 (2)
  - Brown, William, 4 July 1838 (1)
  - Browne, A. A., 29 April 1834 (1)
  - Brownell, T. C., 9 April 1833 (1)
  - Brownell, W. C., 28 September 1837 (1)
  - Brownson, Philo, 18 December 1833-4 June 1834 (2)
  - Bruen, M., 4 June 1829-29 July 1829 (2)
  - Brunson, Alfred, 15 June 1832-27 April 1835 (3)
  - Brush, G. W. and John Lewis, 7 July 1835 (1)
  - Bryan, James, 21 January 1837-27 October 1838 (2)
  - Buck, Ephraim, August 1837 (1)
  - Buckland, H. H., 12 January 1833 (1)
  - Buckley, Samuel B., 16 Ausut 1837-16 February 1838 (2)
  - Budd, Thomas, 20 May 1833-31 October 1838 (3)
  - Budd, William, 25 July 1838 (1)
  - Bugard, B. F., 18 September 1838 (1)
  - Burnap, Uzziah C., 17 December 1829 (1)
  - Burns, S. A., 17 April 1838 (1)
  - Burrill, John T., 13 February 1837-8 March 1837 (2)
  - Burritt, E. H., 14 August 1833 (1)
  - Burtis, Townsend W., 2 February 1833-27 July 1833 (2)
  - Burton, Henry, 14 July 1838 (1)
  - Burton, William M., 2 June 1838 (1)
  - Byrn, Ino W., 23 July 1837 (1)
  - Cahoon, Charles D., 24 July 1826-19 July 1838 (5) (Box 2)
  - Calandrini, Matilda, 17 January 1836-27 January 1836 (3)
  - Calder, Frederick, 4 February 1837-28 October 1837 (2)
  - Caldwell, Merritt, 1 August 1832- 4 August 1835 (6)
  - Calhoun, William B., 29 September 1828 (1)
  - Canfield, R., 4 September 1827 (1)
  - Campbell, G. M., 24 November 1834 (1)
  - Campbell, Randolph, 7 October 1831 (1)
  - Capers, W., 12 September 1833-26 April 1838 (3)
  - Carlton, William T., 8 March 1836-8 August 1836 (2)
  - Carne, Joseph, 11 July 1836-8 August 1836 (2)
  - Carter, Hugh, 11 August 1836 (1)
  - Cass, L., 4 May 1832 (1)
  - Caswell, A., 18 October 1830-24 January 1837 (3)
  - Chamberlain, Parmele, 28 September 1837 (1)
  - Chapman, Henry S., 28 January 1838 (1)
  - Chapman, Thomas, 5 March 1832-28 May 1834 (6)
  - Charles, J. O., 1 July 1837 (1)
  - Chase, Abner, 24 September 1833 (1)
  - Chase, D. H. (Daniel), 17 February 1834-3 July 1835 (2)
  - Chase, Henry, 16 January 1833 (1)
  - Cheney, L. C. (Leonard), 5 November 1833-26 July 1838 (3)
  - Chew, John, 1 September 1832-6 November 1833 (8)
  - Chittendon, Cornelius, 15 March 1837-17 September 1837 (2)
  - Church, Samuel, 1 June 1831 (1)
  - Claiborne, John G., 19 April 1834
  - Clark, Charles B., 17 February 1834-7 April 1834 (4)
  - Clark, Davis W., 10 September 1833-14 December 1838 (5)
  - Clark, E., 20 June 1837 (1)
  - Clark, Horace, 14 October 1833 (1)
  - Clark, J., 14 October 1835 (1)
  - Clark, John, 19 March 1838 (1)
  - Clark, John A., 12 December 1836 (1)
  - Clark, Laban, 1834-19 March 1836 (6)
  - Clark Lorin, 12 April 1838 (1)
  - Clark, Mary, 28 February 1835 (1)
  - Clark, Noah B., 6 November 1837 (1)
  - Clark, Oliver, 17 December 1838 (1)
  - Clark, S. L. H. 12 November 1833 (1)
  - Clark, William, 12 April 1830 (1)
  - Clarke, Dorus, 18 February 1830 (1)
  - Cleveland, Henry R., 30 March 1836 (1)
  - Coggshall, S. W., 29 August 1838 (1)
  - Cogswell, William, 14 January 1834-6 February 1839 (16)
  - Colborn, H., 26 March 1838 (1)
  - Coles, G., 10 December 1830-15 October 1838 (4)
  - Collins, Charles, 24 February 1838-28 May 1838 (2)
  - Colton, Chauncey, 21 April 1835-9 May 1837 (2)
  - Cook, E. M., 5 March 1832 (1)
  - Cooke, C., 24 November 1838 (1)
  - Cooke & Co., 1832 (1)
  - Cookman, George G., 19 April 1831 (1)
  - Cookson, John, 26 June 1835 (1)
  - Coolidge, Clark, 24 June 1837 (1)
  - Copeland, David, 8 February 1832 (1)
  - Copeland, John, 18 April 1835 (1)
  - Cove, J. H., 7 April 1835 (1)
  - Cowles, Henry, 4 September 1834 (1)
  - Cox, G. F., 20 March 1834-23 July 1838 (12)
  - Cox, M. B., 14 January 1831-15 March 1831 (2)
  - Cox, W. A., 31 May 1837 (1)
  - Crain, A. N., 16 September 1833 (1)
  - Crandall, P., 5 March 1833-5 September 1835 (2)
  - Crary, Isaac E., 27 January 1838 (1)
  - Craswell, Joshua, 6 May 1837 (1)
  - Crawford, Elias, 10 March 1838 (1)
  - Cresson, Elliott, 1834-12 February 1839 (6)
  - Curry, Daniel, 6 June 1837-2 August 1838 (3)
  - Curtiss, Samuel P., 6 November 1833 (1)
  - Daggett, Hinman & Co., 4 August 1837-23 July 1838 (2)
  - Daggett, Alfred, 28 June 1833 (1)
  - Daily, William M., 13 July 1837 (1)
  - Dana, Judah, 1 March 1837 (1)
  - Daniel, John, 5 April 1838 (1)
  - David, Virgil, 12 October 1838 (1)
  - Davis, George, 7 January 1833-3 August 1835 (3)
  - Davis, Joseph H., 2 September 1831 (1)
  - Davis, Robert, 3 October 1838 (1)
  - Day, Jeremiah, 30 May 1835-1 October 1838 (4)
  - Day, Thomas, 5 September 1834-14 May 1835 (2)
  - Dayton, A. O., 28 June 1837 (1)
  - Dayton, Smith, 15 January 1839 (1)
  - DeBourcy, William H. 5 September 1834 (1)
  - Delano, J. C., 3 September 1835 (1)
  - Delano, Lewis H., 5 March 1832 (1)
  - Delavan, Edward C., 14 September 1832 (1)
  - Deloutte, I. A., 28 October 1836 (1)
  - Deming, Benjamin F., 20 November 1828-2 April 1834 (5)
  - Deming, Ruben H., 2 September 1835-24 December 1833 (2)
  - Denison, Charles W., 21 December 1833 (1)
  - Dickens, Asbury, 17 June 1837-10 August 1838 (2)
  - Dickerson, M., 22 July 1835 (1)
  - Dickinson, Austin, 26 March 1829-16 April 1835 (3)
  - Disosway, Cornelius R., 4 February 1831-20 January 1835 (5)
  - Disosway, Gabriel P., 22 September 1830-25 August 1838 (12)
  - Dixon, John, 27 June 1838 (1)
  - Dlaklas, Joseph, 2 November 1833 (1)
  - Dodge, Nehemiah, 19 January 1834 (1)
  - Dole, L. P., 13 March 1832-10 August 1836 (6)
  - Dorchester, D., 11 January 1834-30 January 1837 (2)
  - Doughty, Charles I., 28 July 1834 (1)
  - Dow, Caleb, Jr., 30 September 1837 (1)
  - Dow, John, 26 August 1835 (1)
  - Downey, Robert, 19 June 1838 (1)
  - Drake, Benamin M., 10 May 1833-6 July 1838 (5)
  - Drake, Thomas M., 28 August 1831-30 July 1832 (2)
  - Duer, W. A., 15 April 1835 (1)
  - Dunn, N., 11 December 1827-1834
  - Durbin, J. P., 27 September 1831-14 September 1838 (14)
  - Dwight, Lewis, 12 October 1838 (1)
  - Dwight, Theodore, Jr., 5 June 1834-19 August 1834 (3)
  - Dyre, Timothy, 13 March 1832-10 February 1835 (5)
  - Eastman, B. C., 9 April 1833 (1)
  - Eddy, Phebe, 6 June 1828 (1)
  - Edwards, Elishu, 22 November 1832 (1)
  - Edwards, Governor, 27 March 1834 (1)
  - Edwards, Justin, 15 December 1830-1 September 1833 (3)
  - Edwards, William B., 13 December 1837 (1)
  - Ela, D. H., 15 January 1835-28 July 1838 (2)
  - Elliott, C., 20 December 1837 (1)
  - Elliott, Joseph, 9 August 1837 (1)
  - Ellsworth, N. N., 31 July 1838 (1)
  - Ely, Thomas, 20 July 1837 (1)
  - Emmerson, William, 27 March 1835 (1)
  - Emory, John, 1830-7 August 1835 (8)
  - Enos, E., 1822-16 August 1837 (2)
  - Everett, Edward, 27 June 1837 (1)
  - Ewen, Robert M., 25 June 1835 (1)
  - Eyster, C. S., 12 November 1831 (1)
  - Eyster, Jacob, 22 April 1833 (1)
  - Farmer, Thomas, 29 August 1836 (1)
  - Fellows, Francis, 13 December 1836-24 February 1837 (2)
  - Fenner, Robert, 2 February 1838 (1)
  - Ferguson, Samuel D., 23 July 1835-3 August 1835 (2)
  - Ferris, William H., 31 May 1837 (1)
  - Fessenden & Co., 25 July 1834 (1)
  - Few, Ignatius A., 1 March 1833-15 October 1838 (8)
  - Field, D., 18 December 1834-17 March 1837 (3)
  - Fifield, Moses, 1 July 1831 (1)
  - Fifield, Nancy, 23 September 1831 (1)
  - Fillmore, Daniel, 14 September 1837 (1)
  - Fillmore, J., 28 July 1838-18 September 1838 (2)
  - Fish, (Rev.) Henry, 25 September 1836-23 January 1839 (4)
  - Fisk, Caleb, 11 September 1824-16 April 1838 (12)
  - Fisk, Hannah, 25 October 1827 (1)
  - Fisk, Isaiah, 10 June 1812-4 May 1837 (19)
  - Fitch, Maria, 14 August 1827-8 October 1828 (2) (Box 3)
  - Fitch, Silas Jr., 31 August 1838 (1)
  - Fleming, A., 9 November 1827 (1)
  - Fisk, Ruth (Peck), 15 October-1 August 1834 (3)
    See also Peck, Ruth.
  - Flournoy, Josiah, 30 March 1831-12 August 1835 (6)
  - Foot, John A., 2 October 1832 (1)
  - Forbes, James D., 22 September 1836 (1)
  - Fort, Robert W., 14 January 1837 (1)
  - Foster, Eliza, 14 April 1833 (1)
  - Foster, Festus, 8 April 1833-20 April 1835 (9)
  - Foster, Fisher A., 11 February 1834-1 September 1837 (5)
  - Foster, George T., 16 March 1838 (1)
  - Foster, John, 28 September 1826-30 July 1835 (21)
  - Foster, J. W., 2 November 1838-8 December 1838 (2)
  - Foster, Joshua W., 13 November 1834 (1)
  - Foster, Lewis, Jr., 7 April 1835 (1)
  - Foster, William, 24 November 1834 (1)
  - Fowles, J., 26 August 1836 (1)
  - Frazee, B., 27 May 1834 (1)
  - Frazer, John, 27 June 1837 (1)
  - Freeman, Adaline M., 29 May 1830 (1)
  - French, E. with A.V. Blake, 24 December 1838 (1)
  - Frid, Thomas, 12 October 1835 (1)
  - Frost, John, 16 November 1838 (1)
  - Frost, Leonard, 6 March 1830-4 April 1838 (2)
  - Frothingham, Samuel, 31 August 1835 (1)
  - Fuller, Jerah, 30 July 1830 (1)
  - Fulton, Creed, 20 November 1837-27 December 1837 (1)
  - Gale, William, 21 December 1836 (1)
  - Gallander, F. H., 4 July 1831-7 June 1833 (2)
  - Galpin, Daniel, 18 June 1838 (1)
  - Gardner, Daniel, 16 March 1837-1 June 1837 (2)
  - Gardner, Nathan, 20 June 1828 (1)
  - Garnsey, Nathan, 3 January 1831-25 April 1831 (2)
  - Garrettson, M. R., undated (2)
  - Gary, George, 5 August 1833-26 July 1838 (2)
  - Gay, Samuel, 15 January 1838 (1)
  - George, Enoch, 5 July 1824 (1)
  - Gere, John A., 10 January 1832-21 December 1837 (4)
  - Ghu, E. M., 19 November 1838 (1)
  - Gilbert, Elias, 27 August 1835 (1)
  - Gilbert, R., 3 January 1839 (1)
  - Gilder, William H., 17 November 1837-11 January 1838 (2)
  - Giles, William Mason, 16 October 1838 (1)
  - Gillet, Morgan D., 1 October 1838 (1)
  - Gist, J. and others, 19 September 1837 (1)
  - Goodrich, Chauncey A., 13 July 1835 (1)
  - Goodrich, Elisabeth, 18 June 1833-29 June 1833 (2)
  - Goodsell, B., 8 July 1835 (1)
  - Goodwin, Ann C., September 1831-27 January 1834 (5)
  - Goodwin A. S. W., 28 December 1833 (1)
  - Goodwin, Martha, 3 December 1824-7 January 1833 (10)
  - Goodwin, Mary, 23 August 1823-31 March 1826 (2)
  - Gove, John, 12 December 1837-19 January 1838 (2)
  - Goss, Ephraim, 18 March 1835-20 April 1835 (2)
  - Gould, David, 11 April 1827-10 December 1831 (6)
  - Graham, Robert, 23 September 1836 (1)
  - Grant, Isaac, with Mattison Baker, 19 March 1831 (1)
  - Green, Humphrey, 4 April 1837 (1)
  - Green, John C., 11 October 1830-21 January 1839 (11)
  - Green, Timothy, 4 November 1836 (1)
  - Greenleaf, Jonathan, 10 April 1838-25 April 1838 (2)
  - Gregory, Samuel, 15 October 1838 (1)
  - Grew, Henry, 30 March 1832 (1)
  - Gridley, J. S. J., 17 April 1838 (1)
  - Griffen, B., 14 May 1834 (1)
  - Gunn, Allen, 18 September 1838 (1)
  - Gush, William, 20 September 1836 (1)
  - Hale, Harry, 2 February 1835 (1)
  - Hale, Samuel, 24 November 1832 (1)
  - Hall, F., 26 October 1831 (1)
  - Hall, Francis, 21 January 1828-4 December 1837 (10)
  - Hall, John, 13 March 1837 (1)
  - Hall, Wilfred, 18 September 1837-15 October 1837 (2)
  - Hallock, J. K., 15 October 1834 (1)
  - Hallock, L, 4 December 1832 (1)
  - Hambrook, Odden, undated (1)
  - Hamilton, Armor, 27 August 1831 (1)
  - Hamilton, David, 15 July 1835 (1)
  - Hamilton, James, 7 September 1827 (1)
  - Hamilton, Jefferson, 21 June 1836-6 February 1838 (6)
  - Hamlin, Edward F., 25 April 1837 (1)
  - Hanks, Albert S., 17 January 1839 (1)
  - Hannah, John, 13 October 1835-22 December 1838 (2)
  - Harbison, Jeremiah, 4 December 1838 (1)
  - Harden, Samuel, 26 January 1838 (1)
  - Hardesty, R., 4 March 1837 (1)
  - Hardy, John W., 1 January 1831-27 December 1837 (6)
  - Harlow, William T., 2 August 1838 (1)
  - Harper & Brothers, 8 December 1834 (1)
  - Harris, Anna, 17 April 1831-7 November 1831 (2)
  - Harris, Reuben, 16 August 1832-10 August 1838 (3)
  - Hart, N. C., 3 January 1832-8 April 1833 (2)
  - Hartley, Robert W., 25 April 1837 (1)
  - Harvard, -M., 24 May 1837 (1)
  - Harvey, Henry, 30 April 1833-2 July 1835 (4)
  - Harvey, James, 11 December 1833 (1)
  - Hatch, W. T., 11 September 1838 (1)
  - Hawley, Horace, 1 October 1837 (1)
  - Haynie, Ann C., 12 April 1835 (1)
  - Hedding, Elijah, 31 March 1829-19 March 1838 (5)
  - Henderson, John, 18 December 1838 (1)
  - Henry, Joseph, 4 February 1837 (1)
  - Herring, Amos, 22 June 1835 (1)
  - Hewit, N., 13 March 1834 (1)
  - Hick, John, 20 May 1833 (1)
  - Hinman, David, 22 May 1833 (1)
  - Hinsdale, J., 24 August 1832-3 July 1834 (2)
  - Hitchcock, Luke, 28 July 1837 (1)
  - Hobart, A. L., 27 July 1838 (1)
  - Hobart, John, 5 January 1838-10 February 1838 (2)
  - Holbrook, Josiah, 18 November 1833-31 March 1834 (2)
  - Holcomb, Hiram, 24 September 1832-20 June 1833 (2)
  - Holdich, Joseph, 16 April 1835-14 January 1839 (8)
  - Holkins, Harvey, 1828 (1)
  - Holmes, Joseph, 10 June 1837-21 July 1837 (2)
  - Holton, Isaac, 14 April 1834 (1)
  - Hooker, William J., 15 September 1836 (1)
  - Hopin, John, 23 January 1839 (1)
  - Hopkins, V. L., 24 October 1838 (1)
  - Hopkins, William F., 1833 (2)
  - Horton, Jotham, 15 January 1833-10 March 1837 (4)
  - Hotchkiss, John, 23 August 1832 (1)
  - Howe, Bezaleel, 10 October 1838 (1)
  - Howe, John M., 7 December 1829 (1)
  - Howell, Thomas J., 7 June 1831 (1)
  - Hoyt, Benjamin R., 21 November 1828 (1)
  - Hoyt, Philip, 12 July 1837 (1)
  - Hoyt, S., 15 November 1831 (1)
  - Hoxey, Thomas, 4 December 1830-26 July 1835 (7)
  - Hubbard, Oliver P., 20 October 1834-19 August 1835 (5)
  - Hubbard, S. D., 27 June 1833 and undated (2)
  - Hubbard, W. B., 8 September 1834 (1)
  - Huber, J. Frederick, 1 January 1831 (1)
  - Huber, James Henry, 10 January 1839 (1)
  - Hudson, Toby, 15 April 1831 (1)
  - Huestis, A. J., 3 June 1833-7 July 1838 (6)
  - Hughes, John, 5 August 1835 (1)
  - Humason, L. H., 11 April 1835 (1)
  - Hungerford, Charles, and Jared W. Pardee, 26 February 1838 (1)
  - Hunt, Chester, 11 July 1831 (1)
  - Hunt, Daniel I., 17 June 1831-26 August 1831 (2)
  - Huntington, E., 16 May 1837 (1)
  - Husted, J. B., 20 March 1838 (1)
  - Hyde, Charles, 23 January 1834 (1)
  - Hyde, George M., 21 March 1832 (1)
  - Hyde, John, 30 March 1828 (1)
  - Hyer, William, 26 September 1837 (1)
  - Ingham, Samuel, 12 October 1838 (1)
  - Inglis, Joseph L., 13 May 1831-22 November 1833 (5)
  - Inglis, S., 30 April 1834 (1)
  - Ingolls, Samuel, 31 December 1836 (1)
  - Innes, George, 10 December 1833 (1)
  - Ireson, E., 23 February 1832-8 November 1833 (2)
  - Ireson, Mary, 26 July 1835 (1)
  - Irving, Ebenezer, 13 September 1833 (1)
  - Irving, John, 1 December 1836-1 Mary 1837 (2)
  - Jackson, Ebenezer, 23 June 1835-27 November 1838 (3) (Box 4)
  - Jackson, Henry, 29 June 1837 (1)
  - Jannatt, 23 December 1830 (1)
  - Jaques, R. I., 7 April 1835-24 August 1835 (2)
  - Jenks, William, 23 October 1830-29 October 1830 (2)
  - Jennings, A. E., 25 February 1837 (1)
  - Jennings, Isaac, 21 January 1839 (1)
  - Jenerson, I., 1838 (1)
  - Jennison, Isaac, 20 July 1832 (1)
  - Jennison, J., 9 August 1837 (1)
  - Jerome, William, 7 October 1831 (1)
  - Jew, from Charleston, 1 August 1839 (1)
  - Johnston, James, 1836 (1)
  - Johnston, John, 9 July 1835-12 May 1836 (6)
  - Jolly, Hugh, 15 August 1835-18 July 1838 (2)
  - Jones, Benjamin, 23 March 1829 (1)
  - Jones, William, 17 November 1838 (1)
  - Judson, Andrew T., 6 June 1835 (1)
  - Kavanaugh, Benjamin T., 26 July 1838 (1)
  - Kay, & Co., 19 January 1838 (1)
  - Keagy, 6 May 1833 (1)
  - Keener, Christian, 21 December 1830-6 July 1835 (20)
  - Keener, John C., 1 May 1837-27 August 1838 (4)
  - Kellogg, George, 30 May 1838 (1)
  - Kelley, Samuel, 19 September 1832 (1)
  - Kelly, Johnston & Co., 25 August 1835 (1)
  - Kennaday, I., 15 February 1832 (1)